Mss.B.F865
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Nov. 2, 1845; 10x7-3/4; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Philadelphia; Montpelier, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning papers on the magnetic dip for the APS. Refers to Walker.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Nov. 6, 1845; 10x8; Delaware County Institute of Science (Delaware County, Pa.)
    Chester, A.L.S.: J. M. Broomall. 1p. and add. Has been elected corresponding member.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Dec. 19, 1845; 10x8; Hall, James
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Friendly letter. Refers to Haldeman.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, May 19, 20, 1845; 9x7-1/2; Moses, Horace, 1820-1893
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Business.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1846; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Leaves paper on magnetic dip for the APS. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 20, 1846; 10x8; Hall, James
    Albany, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Friendly letter. Refers to H. D. Rogers and Lyell.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 22, 1846; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Friendly letter. Concerning magnetic observations.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 28, 1846; 10x7-3/4; Trego, Charles B., 1794-1874
    Harrisburg, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning Mason and Dixon's line.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 4, 1846; 10x8; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning astronomical paper for the APS.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], April 14, 1846; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning the solar eclipse. Refers to the university of Pennsylvania. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 14, 1846; 10x7-3/4; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end.: "A.P.S...." Asks him to read a paper on the magnetic dip at the APS meeting.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, June 30, 1846; 9-3/4x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, July 1, 1846; 10x8; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning his article on the magnetic dip for the APS.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, July 10, 1846; 10-1/2x8; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for his interest in the papers on the magnetic dip.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, July 14, 1846; 10x8; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning his article on the magnetic dip for the APS.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Sept. 30, 1846; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. with initials. 1p. and add. Enc. wanting. Formerly B F865.b. Asks favor. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Oct. 30, 1846; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning Agassiz. Concerning his woes in publishing in natural history and philosophy.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Nov. 9, 1846; 9-3/4x6-3/4; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Gloucester, A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning the Franklin institute. Mentions Agassiz. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Nov. 24, 1846; 12x7-1/4; Clymer, Edward M.
    Reading, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends specimen of iron ore.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Dec. 5, 1846; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Asks favor. Refers to Joseph Henry, Dunglison, and the academy of natural sciences of Philadelphia. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer?], Dec. 7, 1846; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    A.L.S. 2p. Recommends T. R. Peale as curator of the Smithsonian. Refers to A. D. Bache.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Dec. 7, 1846; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. Encloses article on music for presentation to the Franklin Institution. Refers to F. Peale.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Dec. 9, 1846; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning the APS testimonial for T. R. Peale. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Jan. 1, 1847; 10x8; Norton, William A. (William Augustus), 1810-1883
    Newark, Delaware, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning his theory of magnetism. Refers to his speech before the APS.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, Jan. 9, 1847; 10x7-1/2; Fry, Joseph Reese, d.1865.
    A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends papers for memorial to Wylie.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 30, 1847; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to Joseph Henry, A. D. Bache, Kane, and R. M. Patterson. Film 1249
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 31, 1847; 8x5-1/4; Hall, James
    Albany, A.L.S. 3p. Introduces Ledyard Luicklaen. Refers to Leidy and LeConte.
    Date may not be correct, depending on Dudley Obs. inauguration date. - H. Miller, January 3, 1963
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Feb. 3, 1847; 10x8; Draper, John William, 1811-1882
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning U.S. mint business.
  - Letter to the Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania, March 2, 1847; 12-1/2x8; Alumni, Classes of 1828 to 1845
    Philadelphia; A.D.S. with initials. 1p. Present portrait of S. B. Wylie to University.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, June 14, 1847; 10-1/2x3-1/4; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. Would like to teach at Girard. Personal news.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, July 28, 1847; 10x8; Emory, William H., (William Hemsley), 1811-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Geological news.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Aug. 3, 1847; 10x8; Emory, William H., (William Hemsley), 1811-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Geological and other observations.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Aug. 5, 1847; 10x8; Price, James M.
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning a newly invented steamship.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Aug. 18, 1847; 10x8; Emory, William H., (William Hemsley), 1811-1887
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning geology.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Jan. 18, 1848; 10x7-3/4; Mifflin, S. W.
    Huntingdon, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Asks favor.
  - Letter to [John Fries] F[razer], Feb. 4, 1848; 8-3/4x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Astronomical problem. Refers to the APS and Leidy.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 23, 1848; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 3p. and add. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning his publication. Friendly letter. Education in Philadelphia. Refers to Henry and J. R. Ingersoll.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, March 20, 1848; 8-3/4x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. Friendly letter. Concerning boilers. Refers to the Franklin institute and the APS.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 22, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Asks help to receive government appointment. Refers to J. K. Kane and the Smithsonian institution. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 27, 1848; 5x4; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.h. Friendly letter. Film 1249
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 2, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Concerning the possibility of government employment. Refers to Buchanan, A. D. Bache, Joseph Henry, and the Franklin institute. Film 1249.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, April 3, 1848; 10x8; Roberts, Solomon W., (Solomon White), 1811-1882
    Harrisburg, A.L.S. 1p. Will try to assist T. R. Peale.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, April 5, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Concerning a government appointment. Refers to A. D. Bache. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, April 10, 1848; 10x8; Ingersoll, Joseph R., (Joseph Reed), 1786-1868
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Will try to help T. R. Peale.
  - Letter to [John Fries] F[razer], April 18, 1848; 9x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. Will try to help T. R. Peale. Concerning insects.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, April 21, 1848; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Concerning his publication on magnetism. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fires] Frazer, April 25, 1848; 8-3/4x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. Has written a letter for T. R. Peale.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, May 2, 1848; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p., end. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning weights and measures. Refers to Hassler. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, May 11, 1848; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Business of Hassler. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, May 21, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to Joseph Henry, A. D. Bache, R. M. Patterson, and the Franklin Institute. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, June 2, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to A. D. Bache and Joseph Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, June 7, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Refers to Joseph Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, June 10, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, June 12, 1848; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Annapolis, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Recommends Mr. Goodfellow for job. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, June 14, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, June 25, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, June 28, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, July 3, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.p. Concerning natural history at the Smithsonian. Refers to Joseph Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Aug. 15, 1848; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Aug. 21, 1848; 10x8; Trask, T. S.
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning his subscription to a publication.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Aug. 29, 1848; 10x8; Emory, William H., (William Hemsley), 1811-1887
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning his publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Sept. 6, 1848; 10x7-3/4; Reese, John James, 1818-1892
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning pay for teaching.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Sept. 12, 1848; 10x8; Emory, William H., (William Hemsley), 1811-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning geology.
  - Letter to John Ludlow, Philadelphia, Sept. 28, 1848; 10x7-3/4; Wells, William Harvey, 1812-1885
    Newburyport, Mass, L.S. 1p. and add. Inquires concerning the telescope of the university.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Oct. 12, 1848; 10x8; Mitchel, O. M. (Ormsby MacKnight), 1809-1862
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Business. Concerning the telegraph.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Oct. 24, 1848; 9x7; Torrey, John, 1796-1873
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Asks for recommendation.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Dec. 5, 1848; 7x4-1/2; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Asks favor for a worthy young man.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Dec. 7, 1848; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.b. Asks favor. Friendly letter. Refers to the Franklin institute. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Dec. 11, 1848; 10x7-3/4; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Asks favor. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazier [sic], Philadelphia, Dec. 14, 1848; 10x8; Boynton, J. F.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning mineralogy.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Dec. 17, 1848; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning the survey of the west coast. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], January 2, 1849; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. with initials. 2p. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning coast survey politics. Refers to the APS, the Franklin institute and R. M. Patterson. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 13, 1849; 7x4-1/2; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks favor concerning iron.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Jan. 16, 1849; 6-1/2x4; Page, James, 1795-1875
    A.L.S. 1p. Business.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 29, 1849; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning a report by the A.P.S. Refers to Henry. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 31, 1849; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Hare, George Emlen, 1808-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Feb. 1, 1849; 9-3/4x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 2p. Formerly B F865.b. Concerning the A.P.S. Refers to J. K. Kane. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Feb. 2, 1849; 10x8; Booth, James Curtis, 1810-1888
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning Franklin institute business.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Feb. 10, 1849; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 2p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Refers to the APS. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, March 12, 1849; 12x7-3/4; Sheble, Return
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning experiments on colors and sight.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, March 15, 1849; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Alexander, J. H. (John Henry), 1812-1867
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter. Refers to A. D. Bache.
  - Letter to [William Steven?] Hamilton, April 25, 1849; 10x8; Ewbank, Thomas, 1792-1870
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Business. Friendly letter. Enclosed originally in letter from Ewbanks to J. F. Frazer; April 19, 1851.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, April 30, 1849; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Asks favor. Refers to R. M. Patterson. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, May 2, 1849; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Formerly B F865.p. Concerning Evan Hopkins and his theory of terrestrian magnetism. Refers to the APS, the academy of natural science. and R. M. Patterson. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer,Philadelphia, May 9, 10, 1849; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Formerly B F865.p. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n F[ries] Frazer, May 10, 1849; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Norris Brothers
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces F. P. Dimppel and asks favor.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, May 18, 1849; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Friendly Letter. Concerning publications on geology.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, May 25, 1849; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Formerly B F865.a. Introduces von Chrismar who is here to study mines and mining in the U.S. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, May 29, 1849; 10x8; Loomis, Elias, 1811-1889
    Princeton, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Friendly letter. Concerning the telegraph.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, May 30, 1849; 6-3/4x4-1/4; Booth, James Curtis, 1810-1888
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, June 23, 1849; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, July 15, 1849; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 2p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Concerning the coast survey. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Aug. 10, 1849; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Introduces J. H. Alexander. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Sept. 5, 1849; 10x8; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Nov. 8, 1849; 8x5; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter. Concerning J. L. LeConte. Glad Leidy was made a member of the APS.
  - Letter to [John Fries] F[razer], Nov. 15, 1849; 8x5; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning liquor. Will lecture on phonetics at the Smithsonian. Refers to lecturing at Franklin institute. Refers to LeConte, Henry and Leidy.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Nov. 16, 1849; 8x5-1/4; Marcou, Jules, 1824-1898
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Geology of the U.S. Refers to Agassiz.
  - Letter to [John Fries] F[razer], Nov. 26, 27, 1849; 8x5; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. Friendly letter. Refers to the Franklin institute.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Jan. 4, 1850; 8x5; Patterson,, Robert M., (Robert Maskell), 1787-1854
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Cannot attend the APS meeting.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Jan. 11, 1850; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Thanks for sympathy. Film 1249.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 9, 1850; 10-1/2x8; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Formerly B F865.a. Friendly letter. Would like to deliver some lectures [at the University?]. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Feb. 14, 1850; 8x5; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.a. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Feb. 25, 1850; 8x5; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Formerly B F865.a. Friendly letter. Refers to Dr. Watson of Philadelphia and Dr. Henry of Washington. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, March 27, 1850; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Columbia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Formerly B F865.a. Friendly letter. Concerning his investigation concerning Negroes. Film 1249
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], April 3, 1850; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Potter, Alonzo, 1800-1865
    A.L.S. 2p. Asks for a recommendation for an applicant.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, April 5, 1850; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Philadelphia, April 8, 1850; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Introduces P. A. Siljiström. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 13, 1850; 10x7-1/2; Logan Evening School for Young Men
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: Benj[ami]n Gaskill. 1p. Thanks for his lecture.
  - Letter to [John Fries] F[razer], April 17, 1850; 8x5; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, April 23, 1850; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Wetherill, Charles Mayer, 1825-1871
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Chemical news.
  - Note to [John Fries] Frazer, April 25, 1850; 8x5-1/4; Hare, John S.
    A.N.S. 1p. and add. Introduces Prof. Amarelli who visits the University of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, April 30, 1850; 10x7-3/4; Haupt, Herman, 1817-1905
    Harrisburg, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning mathematics.
  - Letter to [John Fries] Frazer, June 10, 1850; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Wetherill, Charles Mayer, 1825-1871
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. University of Pennsylvania business.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, June 28, 1850; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Wetherill, Charles Mayer, 1825-1871
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the telescope for the university.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, July 9, 1850; 10x8; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning barometers and thermometers. Refers to Agassiz.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Sept. 2, 1850; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Chollet, Mina
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Sept. 9, 1850; 10x8; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Elmira, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Friendly letter. Meteorological matters.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Sept. 17, 1850; 8x6-1/2; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Buffalo, A.L.S. 3p. In French. Concerning his visiting Philadelphia. Refers to Tilghman.
  - Letter to J[ohn Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Sept. 18, 1850; 10x8; Chollet, Mina
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Sept. 25, 1850; 10x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Invitation to [John Fries] Frazer, Philadelphia, Sept. 26, 1850; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Burlington College
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. and add.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Sept. 28, 1850; 10x7-3/4; Association of the Friends of Education, meeting in Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: W[illia]m Vogdes. 2p. Informs him of his position in the organization.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Sept. 30, 1850; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Introduces Senon Marcial. Film 1249.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Nov. 7, 1850; 11x9; U.S. Executive committee...for the industrial exhibition...
    Harrisburg, L.S.: Wm. Jn. Johnston. 1p. Asks that he work with Fraley for the London exhibit.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Nov. 9, 1850; 10x7-3/4; Bache Institute
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: Wm. J. McMullin. 1p. Has been elected a member.
  - Letter to J[ohn Fries] Frazer, Nov. 9, 1850; 7x4-1/2; Humphreys, A. A., (Andrew Atkinson), 1810-1883
    A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Nov. 10, 1850; 10x7-3/4; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    A.L.S. 1p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.
  - Letter to J[ohn] F[ries] Frazer, Nov. 11, 1850; 8x5; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Asks for skull of walrus for the academy of natural sciences.
  - Letter to John F[ries] Frazer, Nov. 12, 1850; 10-1/4x8; Biddle, Craig, 1823-1910
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning education.
  - Letter to John Fries Frazer, November 26, 1850; Bache Institute
    Invites him to give a course of lectures.
  - Letter to John [Fries] Frazer, Nov. 27, 1850; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Phillips, P.
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning mollusks.
  - Letter to [John Fries Frazer], Dec. 19, 1850; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. with initials. 4p. Formerly B F865.b. Friendly letter. Film 1249.